<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Booster Timeline</title>
    <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Booster Timeline</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://science-democracy.github.io/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2 Big Reasons America’s Booster Rates are Lagging</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/boosterlags/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/boosterlags/</guid>
      <description>The two main reasons that Americans are not getting booster shots are issues with timing and political polarization through media consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You probably don&#39;t need another booster</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/you-probably-do-not-need-another-booster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/you-probably-do-not-need-another-booster/</guid>
      <description>Some parts of the immune system sustained, showing strong response to any new coronavirus variant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid News: New York Backs Off Booster Mandate for Health Care Workers</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/ny-backs-off-booster-mandate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/ny-backs-off-booster-mandate/</guid>
      <description>Since around 25% of New Yorkers with a career in healthcare are unwilling to get the booster shot, NYC hospitals are dropping the requirement to get a booster in order to maintain a staff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waning Vaccine Effectiveness</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/waning_vaccine_effectiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/waning_vaccine_effectiveness/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; the effectiveness of double vaccinations and triple vaccinations fall of from 87% and 91% to 66% and 78% respectively</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 booster shot uptake is at all-time low in the US, CNN analysis finds</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/covid-19-booster-shot-uptake-is-at-all-time-low-in-the-us-cnn-analysis-finds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/covid-19-booster-shot-uptake-is-at-all-time-low-in-the-us-cnn-analysis-finds/</guid>
      <description>The statistics and the rate of vaccination as well as booster doses in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussion of fourth shot</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/fourth-shot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/fourth-shot/</guid>
      <description>more nations are discussing the possibility of fourth doses of coronavirus vaccine for their most vulnerable. In the United States, health officials emphasized late last year that fourth doses were not yet needed and said it was too premature to be discussing a potential fourth dose of coronavirus vaccine for most people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most World&#39;s Vaccine Likely Won&#39;t Prevent Infection From Omicron</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/different-categories-of-boosters-have-different-levels-of-effectiveness-in-stopping-omicron-infections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/different-categories-of-boosters-have-different-levels-of-effectiveness-in-stopping-omicron-infections/</guid>
      <description>preliminary research suggests that only the Pfizer and Moderna shots, when reinforced by a booster appear to have success at stopping Omicron infections, while other categories of vaccines, including Sinopharm and Sinovac which make up almost half of all shots delivered globally offer almost zero protection for the new virant. Experts begin to worry about the ability of protection from Omicron in low-and middle-income countries, where there are limited access to effective booster shots and the governments&amp;rsquo; focus is still on delivering first shots</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Vaccine Makers Plan for Annual Boosters, but It’s Not Clear They’ll Be Needed</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/annualboosters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/annualboosters/</guid>
      <description>Debates about whether or not booster shots will be required as new data from Israel comes into the mainstream</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US opens COVID boosters to all adults, urges them for 50&#43;</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/ap-news_-booster-open-to-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/ap-news_-booster-open-to-all/</guid>
      <description>When the booster shot was released to the public, the government urged people to take it, especially state governments that acted before federal officials to allow it to all adults. While some experts worry that the booster may disencourage unvaccinated people to take the first dose, others believe that the temporary boost is necessary for the holidays approaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDC Overrules Advisory Panel</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/cdc_overrules_panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/cdc_overrules_panel/</guid>
      <description>C.D.C. Chief Overrules Agency Panel and Recommends Pfizer-BioNTech Boosters for Workers at Risk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A CDC Panel Backs Booster Shots For Older Adults, A Step Toward Making Them Available</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/cdc-panel-backs-booster-shots-for-some-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/cdc-panel-backs-booster-shots-for-some-people/</guid>
      <description>CDC suggests vulnerable groups receive third dose of COVID-19 vaccine</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FDA Authorizes Booster Dose of Pfizer-BioNTech COVID-19 Vaccine for Certain Populations</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/fda-authorizes-booster-dose-for-certain-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/fda-authorizes-booster-dose-for-certain-people/</guid>
      <description>FDA authorization for a booster dose of Pfizer&amp;rsquo;s Covid-19 vaccine for people in 65 and older, people at high risk of severe disease, and people whose jobs put them at risk of infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F.D.A. Advisory Panel</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/fda_panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/fda_panel/</guid>
      <description>insufficient evidence to recommend third shots for all adult recipients of the vaccine, as Pfizer had requested</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FDA panel recommends limiting Pfizer booster shots to Americans 65 and older, and those at high risk of severe COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/fda-panel-limit-booster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/fda-panel-limit-booster/</guid>
      <description>FDA panel does not recommend boosters for the general population due to insufficient data and disagreements over effectiveness</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Study of Covid Booster Shots Fans Debate Over Benefits</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/nyt-9-15-21-new-study-of-covid-booster-shots-fans-debate-over-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/nyt-9-15-21-new-study-of-covid-booster-shots-fans-debate-over-benefits/</guid>
      <description>As a short period study on the effectiveness of a third booster is released from Israel, Government and health officials debate on whether to push for a booster and for whom, all before the F.D.A has even approved a third dose</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do We Need Booster Shots More than the World Needs Vaccines</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/vaccine-equity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/vaccine-equity/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; Director of the World Health Organization said booster programs “make a mockery of vaccine equity.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement from HHS Public Health and Medical Experts on COVID-19 Booster Shots</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/cdcstatement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/cdcstatement/</guid>
      <description>The CDC and Deparment of Health and Human Services conclude a booster shot will be needed to maximize the effects of the vaccine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pfizer and BioNTech Announce Submission of Initial Data to U.S. FDA to Support Booster Dose of COVID-19 Vaccine</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/pfizer-initial-data-booster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/pfizer-initial-data-booster/</guid>
      <description>Pfizer and BioNTech submitted Phase 1 data as a part of their Phase 1/2/3 clinical trial program supporting the evaluation of a third or booster dose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interim statement on COVID-19 vaccine booster doses</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/whostatement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/whostatement/</guid>
      <description>As debate for vaccines sparks around the world, the World Health Organization releases a statement on their review on booster effectiveness as well as recommendations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WHO calls for halting COVID-19 vaccine boosters in favor of unvaccinated</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/who-halts-boosters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/who-halts-boosters/</guid>
      <description>The WHO calls for a halt on COVID-19 vaccine boosters until at least the end of September as gap between wealthy and poor countries widens. Boosters had begun being debated and used to counter spread of emerging new variants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint CDC and FDA Statement that boosters not currently needed</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/jointstatement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/jointstatement/</guid>
      <description>The CDC and FDA released a joint statement that announced that a booster shot is not needed at that time for those who are fully vaccinated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pfizer to seek FDA authorization for third, booster dose of its Covid-19 vaccine</title>
      <link>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/pfizer-to-seek-fda-authorization-for-third-booster-dose-of-its-covid-19-vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://science-democracy.github.io/news/pfizer-to-seek-fda-authorization-for-third-booster-dose-of-its-covid-19-vaccine/</guid>
      <description>Phizer wants to get a booster shot authorization from the FDA because Phizer&amp;rsquo;s research suggests that antibodies from initial doses are weening</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
